The world was in a mess... but their hair was perfect!!
Hairspray is a comedy, music, romance film directed by John Waters.
'Pleasantly plump' teenager Tracy Turnblad achieves her dream of
becoming a regular on the Corny Collins Dance Show.
Now a teen hero, she starts using her fame to speak out for the
causes she believes in, most of all integration.
In doing so, she earns the wrath of the show's former star, Amber Von
Tussle, as well as Amber's manipulative, pro-segregation parents.
The rivalry comes to a head as Amber and Tracy vie
for the title of Miss Auto Show 1963.
Tracy Turnblad, played by Ricki Lake.
Edna Turnblad / Arvin Hodgepile, played by Divine.
Velma Von Tussle, played by Debbie Harry.
Amber von Tussle, played by Vitamin C.
Franklin von Tussle, played by Sonny Bono.
Penny Pingleton, played by Leslie Ann Powers.
Hairspray is a 1988 American musical comedy film written and directed by John Waters, starring Sonny Bono, Ruth Brown, Divine,
Debbie Harry, Ricki Lake in her film debut, and Jerry Stiller, with special appearances by Ric Ocasek and Pia Zadora.
Hairspray was a dramatic departure from Waters's earlier
works, with a much broader intended audience.
Hairspray's PG is the least restrictive rating a Waters film has
received; most of his previous films were rated X by the MPAA.
Set in 1962 Baltimore, Maryland, the film revolves around self-proclaimed "pleasantly plump" teenager Tracy
Turnblad as she pursues stardom as a dancer on a local TV show and rallies against racial segregation.
Hairspray was a moderate success upon its initial
theatrical release, earning $8 million.
However, it managed to attract a larger audience
on home video in the early 1990s.
The film received critical acclaim and ranks at No.
444 on Empire magazine's 2008 list of the 500 greatest films of all time.
This is Divine's final film released during his lifetime.
He died three weeks after its release.
In 2002, the film was adapted into a Broadway musical of the same name,
which won eight Tony Awards, including Best Musical in 2003.
A second film version of Hairspray, an adaptation of the stage musical, was also released by New
Line Cinema in 2007, which included many changes of scripted items from the original.
In 2022, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of bomb, baltimore, usa,
civil rights, romcom, racial segregation.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.